Guide to the MRNY Downtown Clubbing Collection MSS.523
Fales Library and Special Collections
MRNY Downtown Clubbing Collection
1978-2012
Fales Library and Special Collections
Doyle, Robert
Thompson, Mark
MSS.523
5.75 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 flat box.
Mark Thompson and Robert Doyle are the founders and editors of MRNY, an online style and travel magazine. Beginning in 1998 MRNY focused on documenting the nightlife tailored to LGBTQA culture and society. Both Thompson and Doyle are avid photographers and documented the nightlife culture in downtown New York City; Miami, Florida; and Montreal, Quebec, Canada between 2002 to 2014 on the MRNY Nightlife branch of MRNY. The MRNY Downtown Clubbing Collection consists of publications, ephemera, and other materials collected by Mark Thompson and Robert Doyle documenting their experiences in the New York City downtown nightlife scenes from 1978-2010. The collection includes flyers, members club cards, pins, matchbooks, and magazines, as well as playbills, posters, festival guides, and books related to gay culture in America from 1987 to 2012. Information booklets from festivals in Miami and Montreal, as well as Broadway playbills from the 1990s are particularly well-represented. Collection material before 1995 primarily reflects downtown New York City nightlife while material from the 2000s emphasizes music festivals outside of the city.
Scope and Contents
The MRNY Downtown Clubbing Collection consists of publications, ephemera, and other materials collected by Mark Thompson and Robert Doyle documenting their experiences in the New York City downtown nightlife scenes from 1978-2010. The collection includes flyers, members club cards, pins, matchbooks, and magazines, as well as playbills, posters, festival guides, and books related to gay culture in America from 1987 to 2012. Information booklets from festivals in Miami and Montreal, as well as Broadway playbills from the 1990s are particularly well-represented. Collection material before 1995 primarily reflects downtown New York City nightlife while material from the 2000s emphasizes music festivals outside of the city.
Biographical Note
Mark Thompson and Robert Doyle are the founders and editors of MRNY, an online style and travel magazine. Beginning in 1998 MRNY focused on documenting the nightlife tailored to LGBTQA culture and society. Both Thompson and Doyle are avid photographers and documented the nightlife culture in downtown New York City; Miami, Florida; and Montreal, Quebec, Canada between 2002 to 2014 on the MRNY Nightlife branch of MRNY.
Robert Doyle is the producer of the 1999 documentary We Are All Children of God.
Mark Thompson holds a Ph.D. in American Studies and has written three novels including Wolfchild and My Hawaiian Penthouse. Thompson writes articles for MRNY Style and Travel as well as Travel Weekly, HuffPost, OutTraveler, and Metrosource. He is an active member of the professional associations Society of American Travel Writers and the New York Travel Writers Association.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received.
Gay men -- United States -- Social life and customs.; Nightclubs -- New York (State) -- New York.; Nightlife -- Social aspects -- New York; Festival booklets; Playbills.; Drag balls.; Dance -- Social aspects.
- Club Flyers, 1978-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1-14, Box 2, Folder 1-13, Box 3, Folder 1-5)
- Festival Guides, 1978-2012 (Box 3, Folder 6-10, Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Invitations, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
- Posters, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 4, Folder 5-9, Box 5, Folder 1)
- Playbills, circa 1990s (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
- Bloom, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Bloom, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Bloom, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- XY Magazine, 2007-2012 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Miamigo, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Abercrombie & Fitch, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Next Magazine, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 6, Folder 1)
- Next Magazine, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- Next Magazine, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
- Next Magazine, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Next Magazine, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- LIFEbeat, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Pride Guides, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 6, Folder 9-11)
- HX, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1-9, Box 8, Folder 1-10, Box 9)
- Wigstock, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Art Against Aids, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Relax!, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- A True Likeness, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Coming Out Right, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Circuit Noize, 2001- 2010 (Box 10, Folder 5-8, Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Next Magazine, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Next Magazine, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- HX, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Multiple Magazines, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Festival Programs, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
- The Advocate, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 11, Box 12, Folder 1)
- 27 East, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Out NY, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- The Games Guide, 1994-06 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- 10 Percent, 1994-06-26 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Posters, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Theater Playbills, circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Media Passes, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 8)
- New York Club Cards, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Florida Festival and Club Cards, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Liberty For All, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Gay Men's Health Crisis, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Calvin Klein Jeans, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Black and Blue Festival, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Interview, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Dream Girls, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Buttons, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 14)
- Matchbooks, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 14)